<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Dr. Gang He</title>
<link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://drganghe.github.io/posts.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Dr. Gang He is an energy scholar, researcher, and teacher. He studies and teaches energy systems, energy and climate policy, and clean energy transition.</description>
<image>
<url>https://drganghe.github.io/files/gang-he-profile.jpeg</url>
<title>Dr. Gang He</title>
<link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.8.26</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Renewable integration and AI demand reshaped power grids in 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2026-01-nrct-grid-decarbonization-year-in-review/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
<span class="screen-reader-only">Note</span>Paper
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>Renewable integration and AI demand reshaped power grids in 2025<br>
<strong>Gang He</strong><br>
<em>Nature Reviews Clean Technology</em> (2026)<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z">10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2026-01-nrct-grid-decarbonization-year-in-review/featured.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A substation in Pittsburgh, California; Photo by Gang He</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="standfirst" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="standfirst">Standfirst</h2>
<p>The importance of renewable integration into power grids came to the forefront in 2025. New challenges in stability, storage, artificial-intelligence demand, and policy shifts defined a year that tested whether power systems can become reliable, flexible, and equitable in a net-zero world.</p>
</section>
<section id="key-advances" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-advances">Key Advances</h2>
<ul>
<li>Global renewable electricity generation exceeded coal generation for the first time.<br>
</li>
<li>Investment and research into long-duration energy storage became central to grid decarbonization.<br>
</li>
<li>Surging AI demand accelerated interest in firm, low-carbon power sources.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="main-text" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-text">Main text</h2>
<p>In 2025, for the first time, renewable electricity generation surpassed coal <span class="citation" data-cites="wiatros-motykaGlobalElectricityMidYear2025">(Wiatros-Motyka and Rangelova 2025)</span>, a symbolic and structural milestone in the history of the power sector. This shift was the result of decades of wind and solar deployment, supported by marked cost declines, industrial policy, and net-zero targets. Yet 2025 also revealed deeper challenges to grid decarbonization—extreme weather, rising electrification, and surging loads from artificial-intelligence (AI) data centers all tested grids and highlighted the growing importance of reliability, affordability, and resilience.</p>
<p>These challenges were brought into sharp focus by the Iberian Blackout, a cascading system failure originating from a voltage disturbance that disconnected gigawatts of solar and wind power in Spain in April 2025. As solar and wind push inverter-based generation to high penetrations, the traditional sources of grid inertia provided by synchronous generators are disappearing. The Iberian event demonstrated that renewable-integration challenges are no longer theoretical; they are unfolding on real power systems serving tens of millions of people. The incident accelerated a global shift toward grid-forming inverters, which can emulate the inertial and voltage-control properties of conventional generators <span class="citation" data-cites="icsinvestigationexpertpanelGridIncidentSpain2025">(ICS Investigation Expert Panel 2025)</span>. <a href="https://eepublicdownloads.entsoe.eu/clean-documents/Publications/SOC/20240503_First_interim_report_in_technical_requirements.pdf">European operators</a> moved toward mandating grid-forming capabilities in new installations, while pilot and demonstration programs were launched in <a href="https://www.ceic.com/gjnyjtwwEn/xwzx/202404/72feddf672de4e859517bd9104c2ef2d.shtml">China</a> and the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2023-10/CX-028809.pdf">United States</a>. The blackout became a defining moment for grid decarbonization in 2025, underscoring that system stability must be reinforced alongside rapid renewable expansion.</p>
<p>Flexibility constraints also became increasingly visible in electricity markets. <a href="https://info.montel.energy/-gb-ireland-renewable-curtailment-report">Curtailment of wind power in the United Kingdom and Ireland reached</a> 4.6 TWh in the first half of 2025, and Europe experienced nearly double the number of hours with negative wholesale electricity prices compared to the previous year <span class="citation" data-cites="internationalenergyagencyElectricityMidYearUpdate2025">(International Energy Agency 2025b)</span>. These signals reflect a structural imbalance between accelerating renewable supply and insufficient system flexibility, demand response, and transmission. Battery storage prices continued to decline, although trade tensions <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-15/trade-wars-seen-slowing-battery-price-plunge-in-2025">slowed</a> the pace of cost reductions. The lack of utility-scale long-duration energy storage (LDES)—systems capable of delivering ten or more hours of energy—emerged as a defining constraint on deeper decarbonization <span class="citation" data-cites="dowlingRoleLongDurationEnergy2020">(Dowling et al. 2020)</span>.</p>
<p>LDES commercialization nonetheless advanced in 2025. The first <a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20251009-the-liquid-air-alternative-to-fossil-fuels">commercial-scale liquid-air energy storage facility</a> in the United Kingdom was connected to the grid, and a <a href="https://www.enerdata.net/publications/daily-energy-news/china-commissions-two-hydropower-plants-hebei-and-qinghai-59-gw.html">3.6-GW pumped hydropower plant</a> in Hebei province, China, entered its first year of full operation. Multiple companies commissioned thermal-storage pilots and flow-battery demonstrations, testing their performance at grid scale. Policymakers responded as well: China’s <a href="https://english.news.cn/20251028/efbfd0c774fd4b1c8daeb741c0351431/c.html">15th Five-Year Plan</a> elevated storage as a core pillar of its “new electricity system”; Ireland’s transmission system operator <a href="https://consult.eirgrid.ie/en/consultation/long-duration-energy-storage-ldes-procurement-mechanism-consultation">proposed dedicated procurement mechanisms</a> to deliver 201 MW of storage capacity by 2030; and California’s battery storage capacity reached <a href="https://www.energy.ca.gov/data-reports/energy-almanac/california-electricity-data/california-energy-storage-system-survey">16.9 GW</a>, helping <a href="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/34b106b2">tame its well-known duck curve</a>. Across regions, LDES is increasingly viewed as core infrastructure needed to close the gap between variable generation and continuous load.</p>
<p>Policy developments diverged sharply across regions. China’s <a href="https://unfccc.int/sites/default/files/2025-11/2035%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%9B%BD%E5%AE%B6%E8%87%AA%E4%B8%BB%E8%B4%A1%E7%8C%AE%E6%8A%A5%E5%91%8A.pdf">Nationally Determined Contribution for 2035</a> commits to reducing greenhouse-gas emissions by 7–10% from peak levels, raising the share of non-fossil fuels above 30% of total energy use, and expanding wind and solar capacity to 3,600 GW—more than six times 2020 levels. The United States, by contrast, withdrew from the Paris Agreement for a second time and adopted an energy-independence strategy focused on expanding fossil-fuel production. Modeling suggests that rollbacks of federal clean-energy subsidies could slow U.S. decarbonization and raise emissions and energy expenditures over 2025–2035 <span class="citation" data-cites="jenkinsImpactsOneBig2025">(Jenkins, Farbes, and Haley 2025)</span>.</p>
<p>Despite policy uncertainty, global clean-energy investment reached a record US$2 trillion in 2025 <span class="citation" data-cites="internationalenergyagencyWorldEnergyInvestment2025">(International Energy Agency 2025a)</span>. Lower-income economies emerged as important engines of renewable growth. <a href="https://ember-energy.org/countries-and-regions/pakistan/">Pakistan</a>’s share of solar electricity nearly quadrupled between 2021 and 2024, rising from 3% to 11%. Solar exports from China to low- and middle-income economies surpassed shipments to high-income economies for the first time in early 2025 <span class="citation" data-cites="emberFirstEvidenceTakeoff2025">(EMBER 2025)</span>. Europe continued advancing complementary technologies, with <a href="https://www.blackridgeresearch.com/blog/latest-list-of-largest-biggest-upcoming-green-hydrogen-h2-projects-plants-in-european-union-commission-council">industrial-scale green-hydrogen plants</a> moving toward operation and large carbon-capture hubs in <a href="https://www.iea.org/commentaries/ccus-projects-around-the-world-are-reaching-new-milestones">Northwest Europe</a> shifting from planning to construction. Together, these developments signal a transition from a generation-centric decarbonization model toward a portfolio approach combining renewables, storage, hydrogen, and carbon capture.</p>
<p>Transmission expansion was another defining theme of 2025. The United States adopted <a href="https://www.ferc.gov/media/order-1920-b">FERC Order No.&nbsp;1920</a>, mandating long-term regional transmission planning and cost allocation. China continued extending <a href="https://ember-energy.org/app/uploads/2025/09/China-Energy-Transition-Review-2025.pdf">ultra-high-voltage corridors</a> to connect desert solar resources with coastal load centers. Meanwhile, the <a href="https://asean.org/adb-and-world-bank-group-launch-the-asean-power-grid-financing-initiative-with-the-asean-secretariat-and-the-asean-centre-for-energy-ace/">ASEAN Power Grid</a> and the <a href="https://greengridsinitiative.net/news/climate-finance-principles-to-unlock-grids-financing-finalised-and-endorsed-by-climate-bonds-initiative/">African Green Grids Initiative</a> gained momentum, both aiming to strengthen regional interconnection and reduce dependence on isolated national systems. These initiatives point toward a future of more interconnected and flexible grids.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most transformative development of 2025 was the emergence of <em>energy for AI</em> as a primary driver of electricity demand. As AI models grow in size and commercial deployment accelerates, the energy footprint of data centers has surged, potentially reaching 12% of U.S. electricity demand by 2028 <span class="citation" data-cites="shehabi2024UnitedStates2024">(Shehabi et al. 2024)</span>. This demand wave is reshaping electricity planning and reviving interest in firm, low-carbon baseload power, particularly nuclear energy <span class="citation" data-cites="liuCanChinaBreak2025">(Liu et al. 2025)</span>. Several technology companies announced direct investments and long-term power-purchase agreements with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/16/business/energy-environment/amazon-google-microsoft-nuclear-energy.html">nuclear plants</a>, signaling a shift from annual “100% renewable” targets toward 24/7 zero-carbon energy strategies. At the same time, AI-driven demand is pushing electricity prices upward, with <a href="https://www.cmu.edu/work-that-matters/energy-innovation/data-center-growth-could-increase-electricity-bills">modelling</a> suggesting consumer power bills increasing 8% nationally and up to 25% in some regions in the U.S., raising concerns about affordability and equity, even as electric-vehicle adoption and managed charging are helping reduce system costs in some regions <span class="citation" data-cites="muratoriTrends2025Insights2025">(Muratori et al. 2025)</span>.</p>
<p>By the end of 2025, renewable energy had begun to dominate power systems in several regions. The challenge ahead is scaling this dominance globally while ensuring that decarbonizing grids are reliable, resilient, and intelligent enough to serve rapidly electrifying and digitally intensive economies. Technological progress in grid-forming inverters, long-duration storage, and digital grid management must be matched by ambitious policy reforms, faster interconnection processes, and deeper community engagement. As power systems transmit more electricity from renewables than from coal, aligning technology, investment, and governance will be essential to making renewable integration the backbone of a reliable and affordable net-zero grid—and the foundation for powering the rapidly expanding AI economy.</p>
</section>
<section id="acknowledgements" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements</h2>
<p>The author thanks the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and the ClimateWorks Foundation for supporting research at the Deep Energy and Climate Policy Lab.</p>
</section>
<section id="competing-interests" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="competing-interests">Competing interests</h2>
<p>The author declares no competing interests.</p>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<ul>
<li>SharedIt <a href="https://rdcu.be/eZUji">full-text</a></li>
<li>Preprint <a href="../../files/papers/2026-NRCT-Renewable-Integration-and-AI-Demand-Reshaped-Power-Grids-in-2025.pdf">pdf</a></li>
</ul>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-bibliography"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">References</h2><div id="refs" class="references csl-bib-body hanging-indent" data-entry-spacing="0">
<div id="ref-dowlingRoleLongDurationEnergy2020" class="csl-entry">
Dowling, Jacqueline A., Katherine Z. Rinaldi, Tyler H. Ruggles, Steven J. Davis, Mengyao Yuan, Fan Tong, Nathan S. Lewis, and Ken Caldeira. 2020. <span>“Role of <span>Long-Duration Energy Storage</span> in <span>Variable Renewable Electricity Systems</span>.”</span> <em>Joule</em> 4 (9): 1907–28. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2020.07.007">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2020.07.007</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-emberFirstEvidenceTakeoff2025" class="csl-entry">
EMBER. 2025. <span>“The First Evidence of a Take-Off in Solar in <span>Africa</span>.”</span> <a href="https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/the-first-evidence-of-a-take-off-in-solar-in-africa/">https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/the-first-evidence-of-a-take-off-in-solar-in-africa/</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-icsinvestigationexpertpanelGridIncidentSpain2025" class="csl-entry">
ICS Investigation Expert Panel. 2025. <span>“Grid <span>Incident</span> in <span>Spain</span> and <span>Portugal</span> on 28 <span>April</span> 2025.”</span> <a href="https://www.entsoe.eu/publications/blackout/28-april-2025-iberian-blackout/">https://www.entsoe.eu/publications/blackout/28-april-2025-iberian-blackout/</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-internationalenergyagencyWorldEnergyInvestment2025" class="csl-entry">
International Energy Agency. 2025a. <span>“World <span>Energy Investment</span> 2025.”</span> <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-investment-2025">https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-investment-2025</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-internationalenergyagencyElectricityMidYearUpdate2025" class="csl-entry">
———. 2025b. <span>“Electricity <span>Mid-Year Update</span> 2025.”</span> <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/electricity-mid-year-update-2025">https://www.iea.org/reports/electricity-mid-year-update-2025</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-jenkinsImpactsOneBig2025" class="csl-entry">
Jenkins, Jesse, Jamil Farbes, and Ben Haley. 2025. <span>“Impacts of the <span>One Big Beautiful Bill On The US Energy Transition</span> – <span>Summary Report</span>.”</span> REPEAT Project. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15801701">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15801701</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-liuCanChinaBreak2025" class="csl-entry">
Liu, Shangwei, Gang He, Minghao Qiu, and Daniel M. Kammen. 2025. <span>“Can <span>China</span> Break the <span>‘Cost Curse’</span> of Nuclear Power?”</span> <em>Nature</em> 643 (8074): 1186–88. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z">https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-muratoriTrends2025Insights2025" class="csl-entry">
Muratori, Matteo, Doug Arent, Morgan D. Bazilian, John Bistline, Brennan Borlaug, Austin Brown, Pierpaolo Cazzola, et al. 2025. <span>“Trends and 2025 Insights on the Rise of Electric Vehicles in the <span>USA</span>.”</span> <em>Nature Reviews Clean Technology</em>, October, 1–19. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00108-3">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00108-3</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-shehabi2024UnitedStates2024" class="csl-entry">
Shehabi, Arman, Alex Newkirk, Sarah J. Smith, Alex Hubbard, Nuoa Lei, Md Abu Bakar Siddik, Billie Holecek, Jonathan Koomey, Eric Masanet, and Dale Sartor. 2024. <span>“2024 <span>United States Data Center Energy Usage Report</span>,”</span> December. <a href="https://doi.org/10.71468/P1WC7Q">https://doi.org/10.71468/P1WC7Q</a>.
</div>
<div id="ref-wiatros-motykaGlobalElectricityMidYear2025" class="csl-entry">
Wiatros-Motyka, Małgorzata, and Kostantsa Rangelova. 2025. <span>“Global <span>Electricity Mid-Year Insights</span> 2025.”</span> Ember. October 7, 2025. <a href="https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/global-electricity-mid-year-insights-2025">https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/global-electricity-mid-year-insights-2025</a>.
</div>
</div></section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-citation"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@article{he2026,
  author = {He, Gang},
  title = {Renewable Integration and {AI} Demand Reshaped Power Grids in
    2025},
  journal = {Nature Reviews Clean Technology},
  volume = {2},
  number = {1},
  pages = {13-14},
  date = {2026-01-20},
  url = {https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z},
  doi = {10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-he2026" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
He, Gang. 2026. <span>“Renewable Integration and AI Demand Reshaped
Power Grids in 2025.”</span> <em>Nature Reviews Clean Technology</em> 2
(1): 13–14. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44359-025-00136-z</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>paper</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2026-01-nrct-grid-decarbonization-year-in-review/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2026-01-nrct-grid-decarbonization-year-in-review/featured.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Grant to Study the Drivers and Impacts of Domestic Clean Energy Manufacturing</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Gang He, Kaifang Luo, Michael Davidson, Ahmad Lashkaripour, Ilaria Mazzocco, and Minghao Qiu are awarded a $750,000 new Alfred P. Sloan Foundation grant to study the drivers and impacts of domestic clean manufacturing interventions, resulting from an Open Call on Energy System Interactions in the United States.</description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://deeppolicylab.github.io/files/images/funders/sloan-logo.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>17 Lex Society Feature Story: Research That Powers Change</title>
  <dc:creator>Meghan Goff</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-12-baruch-17-lex-society-feature-story/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="feature-story" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="feature-story">Feature Story</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="../../files/images/17-Lex-Society-Newsletter-Winter2025-Feature.webp" class="lightbox" data-gallery="quarto-lightbox-gallery-1"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/files/images/17-Lex-Society-Newsletter-Winter2025-Feature.webp" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<center>
Note: Click the image to see full view
</center>
</section>
<section id="about-17-lex-society" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-17-lex-society">About 17 Lex Society</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Every Baruchian – past, present, and future – passes through the doors of “17 Lex” (17 Lexington Avenue). The campus building, on the corner of 23rd Street is the site where the Free Academy, the first free public institution of higher education in the nation, once stood. Founded in 2007, <a href="https://bcf.alumni.baruch.cuny.edu/supporters/17lex">17 Lex Society</a> members are leaders in creating the opportunities necessary to build on our, and your, tradition of changing lives for the better.</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-12-baruch-17-lex-society-feature-story/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-12-baruch-17-lex-society-feature-story/featured.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>播客｜到底还要不要合作了？清洁能源全球供应链的收益与前景</title>
  <dc:creator>TanXiaoFengSheng </dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-podcast-global-clean-energy-supply-chains/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<iframe height="175" width="100%" title="Media player" src="https://embed.podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/%E7%AC%AC48%E6%9C%9F-%E5%88%B0%E5%BA%95%E8%BF%98%E8%A6%81%E4%B8%8D%E8%A6%81%E5%90%88%E4%BD%9C%E4%BA%86-%E6%B8%85%E6%B4%81%E8%83%BD%E6%BA%90%E5%85%A8%E7%90%83%E4%BE%9B%E5%BA%94%E9%93%BE%E7%9A%84%E6%94%B6%E7%9B%8A%E4%B8%8E%E5%89%8D%E6%99%AF/id1564195621?i=1000734081426&amp;itscg=30200&amp;itsct=podcast_box_player&amp;ls=1&amp;mttnsubad=1000734081426&amp;theme=auto" id="embedPlayer" sandbox="allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation" allow="autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write" style="border: 0px; border-radius: 12px; width: 100%; height: 175px; max-width: 800px;"></iframe>
<section id="简介" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="简介">简介</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>本期我们邀请何钢老师来讨论全球清洁供应链的题目。何钢老师是纽约市立大学巴鲁克学院公共和国际事务学院副教授，也是纽约市立大学研究生院和大学中心的博导及人口研究所的兼职教授。他主要从事能源系统、能源和气候政策及能源转型方面的研究和教学。他创建了深度能源和气候政策实验室，致力于为深度减排实现碳中和提供深度分析与深度见解。</p>
<p>01:30 嘉宾学术经历：请您简单介绍下学习和研究的背景。您本科和研究生都学习的是什么专业？为什么感兴趣能源与气候研究？</p>
<p>06:02 什么是清洁能源？什么是清洁能源供应链？</p>
<p>10:17 目前全球清洁能源供应链的图景是什么？现在全球版图长什么样（比如光伏为例）？</p>
<p>12:35 中国在哪些环节有优势？这些优势是如何形成的？中国的学习率为什么比别的国家高？</p>
<p>17:00 技术成本为什么会下降？学习曲线的来源是什么？</p>
<p>参见: Kavlak, G., McNerney, J., &amp; Trancik, J. E. (2018). Evaluating the causes of cost reduction in photovoltaic modules. Energy policy, 123, 700-710.</p>
<p>21:25 学习曲线三要素模型的构建</p>
<p>参见: Quantifying the cost savings of global solar photovoltaic supply chains. John Paul Helveston, Gang He*, and Michael R. Davidson.Nature (2022).</p>
<p>26:25 如何看待和理解中国清洁能源产能过剩论？</p>
<p>32:45 对于南方国家清洁供应链的发展是不是一个机遇？</p>
<p>注：巴基斯坦预计到2026年光伏发电达到20%，参见WRI的pakistan-solar-energy-boom报告</p>
<p>36:18 美国进口光伏的健康和气候收益</p>
<p>参见：Imported solar photovoltaics contributed to health and climate benefits in the United States, Minghao Qiu, Gang He*, Peter Marcotullio, One Earth (2025).</p>
<p>40:10 研究人员如何用模型对政策制定提供见解？</p>
<p>44:44 美国清洁能源制造业如何发展？中国的清洁能源出口未来如何变化？</p>
<p>本期剪辑：觉狐</p>
<p>碳笑风生关注全球和中国的能源转型、气候变化和可持续发展问题，特别是中国实现碳达峰、碳中和的科学、技术、政策、政治、经济、社会和文化问题。大家可以在小宇宙播客、喜马拉雅、QQ音乐、Podcast等平台收听我们，我们同步更新的微信公众号“环境科学与政策”会有更多的专业讨论。大家也可以通过留言或在微信公众号“环境科学与政策”联系我们。 开场、转场、结尾音乐来自The Podcast Host and Alitu: The Podcast Maker app.</p>
</blockquote>
<!--
> 备注：为提高可读性，以下按照“主持人／嘉宾”的方式标注发言人，并在不改变原意的前提下做了极少量分句与标点整理。

## 对话干货

**尚炜：** 大家好，欢迎来到“碳笑风声”。我是尚炜。

**明昊：** 大家好，我是明昊。

**何盼：** 大家好，我是何盼。

**明昊：** 今天我们很高兴邀请到纽约市立大学巴鲁克学院公共与国际事务学院的副教授何钢老师做客节目。何老师在可持续发展与能源转型领域成果丰硕，我们之前的多期节目也曾讨论过他的研究。今天想和何老师探讨一个很有意思也很现实的话题：**低碳能源转型背后的供应链**——全球供应链如何支撑全球低碳转型，以及未来在不同选择与权衡下会如何演变。这不仅关乎环境，同样涉及政治与经济等诸多层面。

**明昊：** 何老师的主要研究方向是**能源系统、能源与气候政策以及能源转型**。他在纽约市立大学创建了**深度能源与气候政策实验室**，致力于为深度减排与碳中和提供数据驱动的分析与洞见。其工作发表在包括 *Nature* 在内的多种高影响力期刊。何老师，先和听众打个招呼吧。

**何钢：** 谢谢邀请。大家好，我叫何钢，很高兴参加这期节目。

**尚炜：** 我们常常从嘉宾的成长经历聊起。很多听众仍在求学或职业初期，能否请您简要介绍一下学习与研究背景？本科与研究生分别学的是什么？以及为什么走上现在能源与气候政策这条研究路径？

**何钢：** 我在北大城市与环境学院学习，读的**地理学**本科和硕士；之后在**哥大**读了**气候与社会**硕士，后来去**加州大学伯克利分校**读**能源与资源**博士。研究主要关注**能源系统、能源与气候政策、清洁能源转型**。北大时受张世秋老师、贾峰老师的“环境技术市场化”课程启发，第一次系统认识清洁能源技术以及政策在推动技术扩散中的作用。后来有机会以青年代表参加联合国气候变化大会，近距离观察气候谈判，也更直观地理解了气候问题的挑战——我开始关注气候变化。

**何钢：** 本质上，气候变化是**能源问题**：大规模化石能源使用带来温室气体排放；应对气候变化要求我们从以化石为主的能源系统转向以可再生为主的系统。地理学强调系统性与“人地关系”，特别适合研究涉及**经济、技术、环境与国际关系**等多因素交互的能源议题。我希望把**科学理性**与**人文关怀**结合起来，用**数据与模型**理解系统，同时审视能源转型对人和社会意味着什么。基于这些考虑，我在纽约市立大学创建了**深度能源与气候政策实验室**，希望用数据驱动的方法为政策与决策提供依据。也有幸参与了一些政策过程，例如**中美气候行动工作组**能源转型专家对话、**纽约州《气候领导力与社区保护法》听证**等。

**明昊：** 回到今天的主题——**清洁能源供应链**。近年无论在中国还是美国，“供应链”都是高频词。很多听众会问：**究竟什么是供应链？在清洁能源领域大家在争什么？**

**何钢：** 先厘清几个常用概念：**可再生能源**（强调来源，如风、光、水、生物质、地热）、**低碳能源**（关注碳排放，除可再生外包括核电、CCUS 等），以及更广义的**清洁能源**（关注环境影响，可纳入储能、氢能等）。在中国语境里还常说**新能源**，相对传统化石能源而提出，强调**政策导向、创新与替代**，具有动态性。

**何钢：** 至于**供应链**，简单说就是**从原材料到终端消费**的全链条过程。以光伏为例：从**多晶硅**到**硅片**、**电池片**、**组件**，再到**系统安装与并网**；以电动汽车与风机为例，也包括**采矿、冶炼、制造、安装与回收**等环节。供应链把这条长链**串联**起来，确保你“按下开关，灯就会亮”。在全球化下，清洁能源供应链本质上是一个**跨国网络**，汇聚了经济协作、技术创新与政策协同。

**尚炜：** 如果以光伏为例，**哪些国家与地区**参与了从资源到制造再到消费的过程？

**何钢：** 中国在**硅料、硅片、电池片、组件**等主要环节的全球产能占比**均超过 80%**；在锂电池的**正负极材料、电芯制造**等环节也超过**七成**。但**资源端**具有全球分布特征，例如锂、镍、钴等在**智利、阿根廷、澳大利亚、印尼、刚果（金）**等国集中；**制造端**目前主要在**东亚**（以中国为主，越南、泰国等地增长明显）；**消费端**分布在**欧美、东南亚及新兴经济体**，未来非洲潜力很大。总体格局可概括为“**南方资源—东亚制造—全球消费**”。

**明昊：** 很多人关心**中国如何形成主导优势**，尤其在光伏。

**何钢：** 这是多因素叠加的结果：
- **政策连续性**与长期规划，支撑早期市场形成；  
- **产业集群效应**（长三角、珠三角等），上下游地理邻近，促进协同与知识外溢；  
- **超大规模市场**带来**快速迭代与试错**；  
- **基础设施、金融与要素供给**完善；  
- **学习曲线**中的**规模经济**与**范围经济**叠加，使**单位成本随累计产量上升而快速下降**。  
同时不能忽视**全球合作**：欧美在早期技术创新与政策补贴方面发挥了关键作用，而**中国的大规模制造**把成本再降了一个数量级。

**尚炜：** 为什么清洁技术成本会**如此之快**下降？

**何钢：** 综合驱动：**规模扩大**（单厂从 MW 到 GW 级、自动化提升）、**效率提升**（典型量产效率从十几％到二十多％，实验室更高）、**材料与工艺进步**、以及**原材料价格**等。不同阶段**主导因素**不一：有研究显示，随着时间推移，**技术进步**的贡献上升，而**劳动力成本**的相对作用下降；**规模效应**在中期最显著，后期相对减弱。结论是——**多因共振**。

**明昊：** 您在 2022 年的 *Nature* 论文量化了**全球供应链合作的收益**：若到 2030 年各国转向**完全本土化**，成本将比维持全球合作**高 20%–30%**。能否介绍**如何量化**？

**何钢：** 我们用**学习曲线模型**，核心要素包括：**累计安装量**、**硅价**、以及从“全球生产”过渡到“本土制造”的**十年转型期**。用 2006–2020 年**中美德**的历史数据拟合后，模拟“本土制造”的情景，发现为达到同等装机，美国需多花 **240 亿美元**、德国 **70 亿美元**、中国 **360 亿美元**，合计约 **670 亿美元**。这为**全球协作的经济利益**提供了定量证据，随后被 IMF、世界银行、WTO 等机构的政策报告引用。

**尚炜：** 关于“中国光伏为什么更便宜”，社会上有不同解读：**补贴、劳动力成本、所谓“产能过剩”**等；也有人认为**先进产能并不过剩**，真正过剩的是**落后产能**。您怎么看？

**何钢：** 从**全球气候目标**看，谈“过剩”为时尚早——若到 2050 年全球风光装机需达 **30 TW**，而现在总装机仅**约 3 TW**，**生产与配套投资远远不够**。从**行业运行**看，阶段性或结构性问题确实存在：**落后与先进产能并存、地方“过度竞争”、利润薄弱**等，是成长中的阵痛。对**他国关切**，则包括**安全（断供风险）**、**公平竞争（价格战/倾销担忧）**以及**战略多样性**等，这些更多来自**国内政治经济目标**而非纯经济效率。

**何盼：** 对**全球南方**而言，是否存在“**跨越式**”发展的机会？

**何钢：** 有的。很多国家**无需再建设化石体系**，可直接进入**清洁能源体系**。例如**巴基斯坦**预计到2026年太阳能占比讲从接近**零**升至**约 10%**；**分布式光伏**让原本电网难以覆盖地区也能用上电，进而改善**教育、医疗、妇女与儿童福祉**等公共服务。**一带一路**等合作拓展了**可达性**与**安装能力**，带来难以低估的发展收益。

**尚炜：** 您与合作者近期在 *One Earth* 的研究还量化了**进口光伏**在美国带来的**健康与气候效益**？

**何钢：** 是的。我们估计 **2014–2022 年**，**进口光伏**替代美国化石发电 **3050 亿千瓦时**，减少 **1.788 亿吨 CO₂**，避免**约 595 例**因空气污染导致的过早死亡，合计**健康与气候收益约 280 亿美元**。折算到设备侧，**每千瓦进口光伏年均带来约 180 美元收益**。以 2020 年**组件成本约 300 美元**计，**两年左右即可由社会收益“回本”**。

**明昊：** 但政策上，风险与不确定性难以量化，常被放大。研究如何发挥作用？

**何钢：** **模型不是完美**，但能把“**少许**”的直觉参数化，帮助**对话与决策**。我们的结果告诉政策制定者：**不是 200% 的成本增幅，而是 20%–30%**——这会影响他们的权衡。方法上，也可在模型中进一步纳入**不确定性、主体偏好与博弈行为**等前沿元素，但现实始终更复杂。学术工作的价值在于**把能量化的部分做好**，为公共讨论提供**坚实基线**。

**尚炜：** 回到“美国制造”。在高**软成本**（并网、融资、许可等）环境下，重建本土光伏全链是否可行？

**何钢：** 关键在于能否形成**可持续的产业生态**：
- **可预期且稳定**的政策与市场预期；  
- **配套产业链与人才体系**（而非仅靠关税或补贴“拉一把”）；  
- 在**技术创新**上形成**差异化优势**；  
- 避免“政策急刹车”造成的**投资波动**。  
近期观察到：**制造投资**在政策调整后有所回落，而**能源基础设施与零售终端投资**仍在增长，说明**市场逻辑**依旧，但若缺乏稳定框架，制造端**难以长期竞争**。多中心格局本可提升韧性与竞争，但需要与**气候紧迫性**相匹配。

**明昊：** 展望未来五到十年直至 2050 年，清洁能源供应链可能出现哪些**关键变化与不确定性**？

**何钢：** 可能的演化路径包括：

1. **中国优势延续 + 产能“走出去”**：更多在**东南亚、非洲**等地本地化生产，服务区域市场，但需应对地缘与东道国风险。  
2. **区域化与多中心**：北美、欧洲、东亚各自形成**核心圈层**，在竞争与有限合作中并存，供应链**韧性**提升但**效率**可能受损。  
3. **“可持续—韧性—公正”**三元框架：同时评估**环境影响、供应链风险**与**利益分配**，作为未来政策与企业战略的**共同语言**。  
总之，研究还有很大空间，期待与各位同行与听众继续交流合作。

**尚炜：** 好的，再次感谢何老师的精彩分享，也期待今后就**清洁供应链**的未来展开更多讨论。

**众人：** 谢谢大家！

> 备注：以上对话为ChatGPT生成整理，仅供参考。
-->
</section>
<section id="引用文献" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="引用文献">引用文献</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>John Paul Helveston, Gang He, and Michael R. Davidson. 2022. “Quantifying the cost savings of global solar photovoltaic supply chains”. <em>Nature</em>. 612: 83-87. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05316-6" class="uri">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05316-6</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Qiu, Minghao, Gang He, and Peter Marcotullio. 2025. “Imported solar photovoltaic contributed to health and climate benefits in the United States”. <em>One Earth</em>, 8: 101467. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467" class="uri">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Kavlak, Goksin, James McNerney, and Jessika E. Trancik. 2018. “Evaluating the Causes of Cost Reduction in Photovoltaic Modules”. <em>Energy Policy</em> 123: 700–710. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2018.08.015" class="uri">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2018.08.015</a>.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="相关文章" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="相关文章">相关文章</h2>
<div id="listing-related-posts" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-default">
<div class="list quarto-listing-default">
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="0" data-categories="cGFwZXIlMkNpbmZvZ3JhcGhpYw==" data-listing-date-sort="1759896000000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1766082586772" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="2" data-listing-word-count-sort="243">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/featured.png" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/index.html" class="no-external">Imported solar photovoltaics contributed to health and climate benefits in the United States</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>We estimate that imported solar panels in the U.S. displaced 305 TWh of fossil generation, avoided 178 million tons of CO<sub>2</sub>, and prevented…</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Oct 8, 2025
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
Minghao Qiu, Gang He, Peter Marcotullio
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="1" data-categories="Y29tbWVudGFyeQ==" data-listing-date-sort="1701752400000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1714754169037" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="6" data-listing-word-count-sort="1134">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2023-12-just-resilient-sustainable-clean-energy-supply-chains/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2023-12-just-resilient-sustainable-clean-energy-supply-chains/cop28.png" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2023-12-just-resilient-sustainable-clean-energy-supply-chains/index.html" class="no-external">Advancing a just, resilient, and sustainable clean energy supply chain</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2023-12-just-resilient-sustainable-clean-energy-supply-chains/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>The global clean energy supply chain stands at a critical intersection of immense benefits and pressing challenges.</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2023-12-just-resilient-sustainable-clean-energy-supply-chains/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Dec 5, 2023
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
Gang He, Daniel M Kammen, Muhammad Husni Mubarok, Shoon So Oo
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="2" data-categories="cGFwZXIlMkNwb3N0ZXIlMkNzbGlkZXM=" data-listing-date-sort="1666756800000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1768599416910" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="19" data-listing-word-count-sort="3623">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2022-10-nature-cost-savings-of-global-solar-pv-value-chains/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2022-10-nature-cost-savings-of-global-solar-pv-value-chains/featured.jpg" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2022-10-nature-cost-savings-of-global-solar-pv-value-chains/index.html" class="no-external">Quantifying the cost savings of global solar photovoltaic supply chains</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2022-10-nature-cost-savings-of-global-solar-pv-value-chains/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>Globalized supply chain has saved solar installers in the U.S., Germany, and China $67B 2008-2020, and solar prices will be 20-30% higher in 2030 if…</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2022-10-nature-cost-savings-of-global-solar-pv-value-chains/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Oct 26, 2022
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
John Paul Helveston, Gang He, Michael R. Davidson
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">No matching items</div>

</div>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>podcast</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-podcast-global-clean-energy-supply-chains/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-podcast-global-clean-energy-supply-chains/featured.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="58" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Imported solar photovoltaics contributed to health and climate benefits in the United States</title>
  <dc:creator>Minghao Qiu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peter Marcotullio</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
<span class="screen-reader-only">Note</span>Paper
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>Imported solar photovoltaics contributed to health and climate benefits in the United States<br>
Minghao Qiu, <strong>Gang He</strong>*, Peter Marcotullio<br>
<em>One Earth</em> (2025)<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467">10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/featured.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Monetized climate and health benefits of importing 1 kW solar panels</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>Global supply chains have played a central role in driving down solar photovoltaic (PV) costs and accelerating deployment globally, but their broader societal benefits are underexplored. Here we quantify the climate, air quality, and health impacts of imported solar panels in the United States between 2014 and 2022. We find that 1 kW of imported solar capacity yields an average of $180 in annualized climate and health benefits, offsetting nearly half the PV module cost in 2020. This imported capacity displaced fossil generation by 305 TWh, avoided 178 million tons of CO<sub>2</sub>, and prevented an estimated 595 premature deaths between 2014 and 2022. While these advantages are unevenly distributed across regions and demographic groups, residents in non-importing states also benefited from them. These findings provide critical evidence for policy debates on clean energy trade, showing that imported solar capacity delivers substantial public health and climate gains beyond direct cost savings.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/figure3.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Avoided emissions and PM2.5-related health benefits associated with electricity generation from imported solar panels</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<p>Published <a href="https://www.cell.com/one-earth/abstract/S2590-3322(25)00293-3">paper</a></p>
<p>Preprint <a href="../../files/papers/2025-one-earth-health-climate-benefits-of-imported-solar-pv-in-the-united-states.pdf">pdf</a></p>
<p>Zenodo <a href="https://zenodo.org/records/16622349">data and resources</a></p>
<p>Release <a href="https://deeppolicylab.github.io/news/2025-10-08-one-earth-imported-solar-pv-health-and-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states.html">summary</a></p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://d1bxh8uas1mnw7.cloudfront.net/assets/embed.js"></script>
<div class="altmetric-embed" data-badge-popover="right" data-badge-type="donut" data-hide-no-mentions="true" data-doi="10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467">

</div>
<span class="__dimensions_badge_embed__" data-doi="10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467" data-hide-zero-citations="true" data-style="small_circle"></span>
<script async="" src="https://badge.dimensions.ai/badge.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</section>
<section id="infographic" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="infographic">Infographic</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/Infographic.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Credit: Jason M. Epstein and Marxe Communications team</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-citation"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@article{qiu2025,
  author = {Qiu, Minghao and He, Gang and Marcotullio, Peter},
  title = {Imported Solar Photovoltaics Contributed to Health and
    Climate Benefits in the {United} {States}},
  journal = {One Earth},
  volume = {8},
  number = {11},
  pages = {101467},
  date = {2025-10-08},
  url = {https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467},
  doi = {10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-qiu2025" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Qiu, Minghao, Gang He, and Peter Marcotullio. 2025. <span>“Imported
Solar Photovoltaics Contributed to Health and Climate Benefits in the
United States.”</span> <em>One Earth</em> 8 (11): 101467. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2025.101467</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>paper</category>
  <category>infographic</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-10-oneearth-imported-solar-pv-health-climate-benefits-in-the-united-states/featured.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="79" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Climate Week NYC 2025: The Role of Nuclear Energy in Decarbonization and Powering the AI Era</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Join us to discuss the role of nuclear energy in decarbonization and powering the AI era during Climate Week NYC 2025.</description>
  <category>event</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/images/Climate-Week-Webinare-2025.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Production Gap Report 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>SEI, Climate Analytics, IISD</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://productiongap.org/2025report/"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/featured.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></a></p>
<figcaption>Production Gap Report 2025</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="summary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>This year’s report updates the analysis presented in the 2023 Production Gap Report, profiling the plans and projections of 20 major fossil fuel-producing countries, representing a mix of the world’s largest producers, large producers with readily available data, and producers with strongly stated climate ambitions.</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<p>Check official <a href="https://productiongap.org/2025-press/" class="external" target="_blank">release</a>.</p>
<p>Production Gap Report 2025 full report <a href="https://productiongap.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/PGR2025_full_web.pdf" class="external" target="_blank">pdf</a></p>
</section>
<section id="main-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-findings">Main findings</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<ul>
<li>Since the 2023 analysis, governments now plan even higher levels of coal production to 2035 and gas production to 2050. Planned oil production continues to increase to 2050.</li>
<li>To meet Paris Agreement goals of holding warming to well below 2°C while pursuing efforts to limit warming to 1.5°C, the world must now undertake steeper and faster reductions in fossil fuel production to compensate for lack of progress so far. Meanwhile, governments expanding fossil fuel infrastructure waste public funds on development destined to become stranded assets.</li>
<li>Achieving these reductions will require deliberate, coordinated policies to ensure a just transition away from fossil fuels. While a few major fossil-fuel-producing countries have begun to align production plans with national and international climate goals, most still have not.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/Figure-ES.2-and-2.2.webp" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>The increases in fossil fuel production estimated under the government plans and projections pathways would lead to global production levels in 2030 that are 500%, 31%, and 92% higher for coal, oil, and gas, respectively, than the median 1.5ºC-con­sistent pathway. These plans and projections also collectively exceed the fossil fuel production implied by countries’ own climate mitigation pledges by 35% in 2030 and 141% in 2050.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="contributors" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contributors">Contributors</h2>
<p><a href="https://productiongap.org/2025report/"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/pgr2025-contributors.webp" class="img-fluid"></a></p>
</section>
<section id="related-posts" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-posts">Related Posts</h2>
<div id="listing-related-posts" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-default">
<div class="list quarto-listing-default">
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="0" data-categories="bmV3cyUyQ291dHJlYWNo" data-listing-date-sort="1699419600000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1729966241123" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="3" data-listing-word-count-sort="436">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2023-11-unep-production-gap-report-2023/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2023-11-unep-production-gap-report-2023/featured.jpg" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2023-11-unep-production-gap-report-2023/index.html" class="no-external">UNEP releases the Production Gap Report 2023</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2023-11-unep-production-gap-report-2023/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>Gang joins a global expert team that contributed to the Production Gap Report 2023</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2023-11-unep-production-gap-report-2023/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Nov 8, 2023
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
SEI, Climate Analytics, E3G, IISD, UNEP
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">No matching items</div>

</div>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>outreach</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-09-production-gap-report-2025/featured.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="105" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Included in World’s Top 2% Scientists List 2025</title>
  <dc:creator>Stanford/Elsevier </dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Grateful to be included in the <strong><a href="https://topscinet.com/scientist_profile/He,%20Gang/2004/?stype=single_year" class="external" target="_blank">Stanford/Elsevier Top 2% Scientists List 2025</a></strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Enabling &amp; Strategic Technologies
<ul>
<li>Environmental Sciences</li>
<li>Energy</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>This is the second time I’ve been included in this list. I want to take a moment to thank my family, current and former students, visiting scholars, mentors, collaborators, funders, editors, reviewers, and colleagues for their invaluable support.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://topscinet.com/scientist_profile/He,%20Gang/2004/?stype=single_year"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/files/awards/Top2PercentScientists2025.webp" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="related-posts" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-posts">Related Posts</h2>
<div id="listing-related-posts" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-default">
<div class="list quarto-listing-default">
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="0" data-categories="bmV3cyUyQ3JlY29nbml0aW9uJTJDdmlkZW8=" data-listing-date-sort="1726545600000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1762864749991" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="2" data-listing-word-count-sort="229">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../files/awards/Top2Percent.png" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/index.html" class="no-external">Included in World’s Top 2% Scientists List 2024</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>Thank you for supporting our work!</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Sep 17, 2024
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
Stanford/Elsevier
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">No matching items</div>

</div>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>recognition</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/awards/Top2Percent.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="81" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Selected as Public Intellectuals Program Fellow</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Gang He is Selected for Ninth Round of Public Intellectuals Program Fellow of the National Committee on US-China Relations.</description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>recognition</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/images/pip-fellow-2025.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="75" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can China break the ‘cost curse’ of nuclear power?</title>
  <dc:creator>Shangwei Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Minghao Qiu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daniel M. Kammen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<!--Include academic icons or bottons-->
<!-- 
Load Academicons v1: https://jpswalsh.github.io/academicons/
-->
<p><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/jpswalsh/academicons@1/css/academicons.min.css"></p>
<p><link rel="stylesheet" href="http://maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome/4.3.0/css/font-awesome.min.css"></p>
<!---
The following code are needed to show dimension citation and altmetrics.
https://api.altmetric.com/embeds.html
https://badge.dimensions.ai/
--->
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://d1bxh8uas1mnw7.cloudfront.net/assets/embed.js"></script>
<script async="" src="https://badge.dimensions.ai/badge.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<script type="text/javascript" src="//cdn.plu.mx/widget-popup.js"></script>
<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-warning callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
<span class="screen-reader-only">Warning</span>Online Version
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>Title: <strong>China reins in the spiralling construction costs of nuclear power — what can other countries learn?</strong></p>
<p>Strengthening regulations and domestic supply chains could be key to making nuclear power more economically viable.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02341-z"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/cover-page.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" style="width:80.0%"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<figcaption>Cover page of the paper</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
<span class="screen-reader-only">Note</span>Paper
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>Can China break the ‘cost curse’ of nuclear power?<br>
Shangwei Liu*, <strong>Gang He</strong>*, Minghao Qiu, and Daniel M. Kammen<br>
<em>Nature</em> (2025)<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z">10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<section id="summary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Escalating construction expenses threaten to derail global progress on atomic energy. China offers lessons on how to rein in costs. Over the past two decades, China has been the main country to substantially and consistently expand its nuclear fleet. Here we compiled and analyzed a dataset on the construction costs of nuclear power plants in China. We find that the construction costs of Chinese nuclear power plants have been declining since 2000, and the cost of building a nuclear power plant has been halved. China’s deliberate, staged effort to build domestic supply chains and standardized reactor designs has been key to this success. Coordinated regulatory structures and long-term policy commitments have also been important. As countries rush to expand nuclear capacities, they must combine affordability with safety, scalability, investor confidence and public trust. Without this, nuclear power will remain an expensive bet the world can ill afford.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/fig1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Figure 1: Overnight construction costs of commercial nuclear power units in the US, France, and China. Overnight construction cost refers to the capital cost of building a nuclear power plant, excluding financing charges incurred during the construction period.<sup>1</sup></figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/fig2.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" style="width:80.0%"></p>
<figcaption>Figure 2: The effect of indigenization (domestic content rate) on unit overnight construction costs of Chinese operating nuclear power plants. Each dot represents a nuclear power plant (including multiple units), as costs and domestic content rates are typically reported at this level. The dashed line represents the fitted linear regression of domestic content rate against unit overnight construction costs.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<p>Published <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02341-z">paper</a></p>
<p>SharedIt <a href="https://rdcu.be/eyaXW">full text</a></p>
<p>Preprint <a href="../../files/papers/2025-nature-nuclear-costs.pdf">pdf</a></p>
<p>Press <a href="https://deeppolicylab.github.io/news/2025-07-28-nature-comment-nuclear-costs.html">release</a></p>
<p>Supplementary information <a href="https://media.nature.com/original/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02341-z/51274736">pdf</a></p>
<p>Source <a href="https://www.nature.com/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02341-z/51274734">data</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Power plant level investment costs (overnight construction costs)</li>
<li>Power plant indigenization rate (domestic content rate)</li>
<li>Harmonized nuclear power plant costs across countries (U.S., France, China)</li>
</ul>
<p>Nature Portfolio <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/NZ6mnx_a46Fj0xepdMsluA">summary</a> in Chinese</p>
<script async="" src="https://badge.dimensions.ai/badge.js" charset="utf-8"></script><span class="__dimensions_badge_embed__" data-doi="10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z" data-hide-zero-citations="true" data-style="small_circle"></span> 
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://d1bxh8uas1mnw7.cloudfront.net/assets/embed.js"></script><div class="altmetric-embed" data-badge-popover="right" data-badge-type="donut" data-doi="10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z"></div>
</section>
<section id="nature-press-release" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="nature-press-release"><em>Nature</em> press release</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><strong>Comment: China Offers Clues to Break Nuclear Power’s ‘Cost Curse’</strong></p>
<p>While historically the nuclear industry has faced a ‘cost escalation curse’, as witnessed in the U.S. and France, China has halved and stabilized these expenses over the past two decades, according to a Comment piece published in Nature this week.</p>
<p>Shangwei Liu, Gang He, Minghao Qiu, and Daniel Kammen compiled and analysed a data set on the construction costs of nuclear power plants in China drawn from a wide range of publicly available sources. They attribute this success to a strategic blend of stable regulations, domestic supply chain development, and standardized reactor designs. China’s centralized nuclear regulatory structure, long-term policy commitments, and rapid project execution have enabled it to build reactors in nearly half the time of recent Western counterparts. These findings have important implications for policymakers seeking a nuclear energy resurgence, “As countries rush to expand nuclear capacities, they must combine affordability with safety, scalability, investor confidence and public trust. Without this, nuclear power will remain an expensive bet the world can ill afford”, they conclude.</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="the-economist-and-the-new-york-times-reproduced-our-chart" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-economist-and-the-new-york-times-reproduced-our-chart"><em>The Economist</em> and <em>The New York Times</em> reproduced our chart</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://www.economist.com/business/2025/09/04/why-nuclear-is-now-a-booming-industry"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/the-economist-energy-bills-chart.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<figcaption>Source: The Economist, September 4, 2025, Why nuclear is now a booming industry.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/10/22/climate/china-us-nuclear-energy-race.html"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/NYT-nuclear-costs-chart.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" style="width:80.0%"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<figcaption>Source: The New York Times, October 23, 2025, How China Raced Ahead of the U.S. on Nuclear Power.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="linkedin" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="linkedin">LinkedIn</h2>
<iframe class="linkedin-post" src="https://www.linkedin.com/embed/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7355643824590782465" height="1062" width="504" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" title="Embedded post"></iframe>
<!--
```{=html}
<style>
  /* Style for screens with a width less than 550px */
  @media (max-width: 550px) {
    iframe {
      width: 100%;
      height: auto;
    }
  }
</style>
<iframe src="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7355643824590782465/" height="1000" width="550" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" title="Embedded post"></iframe>
```
-->
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-bibliography"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">References</h2><div id="refs" class="references csl-bib-body hanging-indent" data-entry-spacing="0">
<div id="ref-rothwellProjectedElectricityCosts2022" class="csl-entry">
Rothwell, Geoffrey. 2022. <span>“Projected Electricity Costs in International Nuclear Power Markets.”</span> <em>Energy Policy</em> 164 (May): 112905. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2022.112905">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2022.112905</a>.
</div>
</div></section><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p><strong>Clarification regarding Flamanville 3 cost estimates</strong>: At the time of our data collection, Flamanville 3 was still under construction, with published overnight cost estimates ranging from $4.013/W to $8.62/W <span class="citation" data-cites="rothwellProjectedElectricityCosts2022">(see Rothwell 2022, Table 2)</span>. In our original figure (now included as <a href="https://media.nature.com/original/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02341-z/51274736">Supplementary Figure S1</a>), we used the lower bound estimate of $4/W and denoted it as “&gt; $4/W” to reflect the uncertainty and acknowledge that this conservative value already illustrates the magnitude of cost escalation in France’s recent nuclear construction. Subsequently, the <a href="https://www.ccomptes.fr/fr/publications/la-filiere-epr-une-dynamique-nouvelle-des-risques-persistants">2025 French Court of Auditors’ review</a> placed the overnight construction cost at over $10/W. We note that the “&gt;” symbol was inadvertently omitted from the final published figure, and we apologize for this oversight.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-citation"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@article{liu2025,
  author = {Liu, Shangwei and He, Gang and Qiu, Minghao and M. Kammen,
    Daniel},
  title = {Can {China} Break the “Cost Curse” of Nuclear Power?},
  journal = {Nature},
  volume = {643},
  pages = {1186-1188},
  date = {2025-07-31},
  url = {https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02341-z},
  doi = {10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-liu2025" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Liu, Shangwei, Gang He, Minghao Qiu, and Daniel M. Kammen. 2025.
<span>“Can China Break the <span>‘Cost Curse’</span> of Nuclear
Power?”</span> <em>Nature</em> 643 (July): 1186–88. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z">https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02341-z</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>paper</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-07-nature-breaking-the-cost-curse-of-nuclear-power/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="81" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Macro-Energy Systems Speaker Series: Supply Chains in Energy Systems</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Join us to discuss how macro-energy systems analysis can better capture critical supply chain risks.</description>
  <category>event</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/flyers/20250701mes-supply-chains-flyer-small.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="106" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Third Annual Conference on Climate Research, Teaching, and Collaboration</title>
  <dc:creator>Baruch Climate Conference</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-03-06-third-baruch-climate-conference/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><a href="https://www.baruch.cuny.edu/climateconference/"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-03-06-third-baruch-climate-conference/featured.webp" class="img-fluid"></a></p>
<section id="third-annual-conference-on-climate-research-teaching-and-collaboration" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="third-annual-conference-on-climate-research-teaching-and-collaboration">Third Annual Conference on Climate Research, Teaching, and Collaboration</h2>
<p>Thursday, Mar.&nbsp;6 10 am–4:30 pm Information and Technology Building Rackow Conference Center, Room 750</p>
<p><strong>Multidisciplinary Climate Research and Teaching</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We will highlight the innovative climate research of our Baruch and CUNY faculty from the Austin W. Marxe School of Public and International Affairs, Weissman School of Arts and Sciences, and Zicklin School of Business. Presenters will share their research about the many ways in which climate change is impacting our lives. A Dean’s Panel will highlight interdisciplinary coordination. Hear from Jessica Lang, Dean, Weissman School of Arts and Sciences; Sherry Ryan, Dean, Marxe School of Public and International Affairs; and Bruce Weber, Dean, Zicklin School of Business.</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="registration" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="registration">Registration</h2>
<p>9:45–10:10 am</p>
</section>
<section id="welcome" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="welcome">Welcome</h2>
<p>10:10–10:15 am</p>
<p>Linda Essig, Provost, Baruch College, CUNY</p>
<p>Chester Zarnoch, Weissman School of Arts and Sciences, Baruch College, CUNY</p>
</section>
<section id="group-1-research-presentations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="group-1-research-presentations">Group 1: Research Presentations</h2>
<p>10:15–11:15 am</p>
<ul>
<li>Refining Carbon Isotope Proxies for Paleo pCO₂: Advances and Challenges in Climate Reconstruction, Ana Gonzalez-Nayeck, Assistant Professor, Natural Sciences</li>
<li>The Role of Disturbance in Ant Behavioral Biodiversity and Invasive Potential, Sarah Bengston, Assistant Professor, Natural Sciences</li>
<li>From the Classroom to Alice’s Rabbit Hole in Wonderland: Curious Nature Exhibit, Sochuiwon Priscilla, PhD Candidate, CUNY Graduate Center</li>
<li>Celebrating Five Years of the Susan Locke Seminar, Chester Zarnoch, Professor, Natural Sciences</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="break" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="break">Break</h2>
<p>11:15–11:30 am</p>
</section>
<section id="group-2-research-presentations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="group-2-research-presentations">Group 2: Research Presentations</h2>
<p>11:25 am–12:10 pm</p>
<ul>
<li>Permaculture, Potatoes, and Peas: Climate and Culture Considerations in Writing 2150, Evelyn Adler, Adjunct Professor, English</li>
<li>Toward a Political Ecology of Insect Conservation in Agricultural Landscapes, Ben Iuliano, Doctoral Lecturer, Natural Sciences</li>
<li>The Power of Framing: How Labeling Influences Plant-Based Food Choices in the U.S., Patrycja Sleboda, Assistant Professor, Psychology</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="deans-panel-interdisciplinary-collaboration" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="deans-panel-interdisciplinary-collaboration">Deans’ Panel: Interdisciplinary Collaboration</h2>
<p>12:10–1:15 pm</p>
<p>Moderator: Samantha McBride, Adjunct Assistant Professor, Public Affairs</p>
<ul>
<li>Jessica Lang, Dean of the Weissman School of Arts and Sciences</li>
<li>Sherry Ryan, Marxe Dean</li>
<li>Bruce Weber, Dean, Zicklin School of Business</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="lunch" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lunch">Lunch</h2>
<p>1:15 –2:10 pm</p>
</section>
<section id="group-3-research-presentations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="group-3-research-presentations">Group 3: Research Presentations</h2>
<p>2:10–2:55 pm</p>
<ul>
<li>Extreme Weather and Mortality of Vulnerable Urban Populations: An Examination of Temperature and Unclaimed Deaths in New York City, Frank Heiland, Professor, Public Affairs and Selen Özdoğan, PhD Student, Economics, CUNY Graduate Center</li>
<li>Disaster Displacement in the U.S., Deborah Balk, Professor, Public Affairs and Jenna Tipaldo, PhD Student, Environmental and Planetary Health Sciences, CUNY School of Public Health</li>
<li>Establishing a Weather Station Network in India Covering Eight States – Public Diplomacy in Action, Neal Phillip, Professor &amp; Chairperson and Paramita Sen, Lecturer, Chemistry, Earth Sciences, and Environmental Sciences, Bronx Community College</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="break-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="break-1">Break</h2>
<p>2:55–3:05 pm</p>
</section>
<section id="group-4-research-presentations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="group-4-research-presentations">Group 4: Research Presentations</h2>
<p>3:05–4:05 pm</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Health and Climate Benefits of Solar Photovoltaic in European Countries and the Role of Imports</strong>, <strong>Gange He</strong>, Assistant Professor, Public Affairs</p></li>
<li><p>Understanding The World Bank’s Role in Climate Finance, Asli Leblebicioglu, Associate Professor, Public Affairs</p></li>
<li><p>Saving the Environment Through Corporate Governance: “Real ESG” as a Cure for Democracy’s Failings, David Rosenberg, Associate Professor, Law</p></li>
<li><p>Climate and the Food-Energy-Water-Waste Nexus: From the Viewpoint of Waste, Samantha McBride, Adjunct Assistant Professor, Public Affairs</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="closing-remarks" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="closing-remarks">Closing Remarks</h2>
<p>4:05–4:15 pm</p>
<p>Chester Zarnoch, Weissman School of Arts and Sciences</p>
<p>Welcome to join us to learn more about climate-related activities at CUNY.</p>
</section>
<section id="conference-website" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conference-website">Conference Website</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.baruch.cuny.edu/climateconference/" class="uri">https://www.baruch.cuny.edu/climateconference/</a></p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>event</category>
  <category>presentation</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-03-06-third-baruch-climate-conference/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-03-06-third-baruch-climate-conference/featured.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Joining the Doctoral Faculty of the Earth and Environmental Sciences Program at the Graduate Center</title>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-01-joining-doctoral-faculty-ees-graduate-center/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/people/gang-he"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-01-joining-doctoral-faculty-ees-graduate-center/featured.webp" class="img-fluid figure-img"></a></p>
<figcaption>EES Program</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>I’m joining the <a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences" class="external" target="_blank">Earth and Environmental Sciences</a> (EES) program at the Graduate Center, City University of New York, as a <a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/people/gang-he">doctoral faculty</a>.</p>
<p>Welcome motivated doctoral students to work with us through the EES program.</p>
<section id="about-the-ees-program" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-the-ees-program">About the EES Program</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>From its inception in 1983, the Ph.D.&nbsp;Program in Earth and Environmental Sciences has identified itself with “promoting teaching and research in the study of the earth.” With faculty in atmospheric sciences, environmental sciences, environmental psychology, geography, and geology, the Earth and Environmental Sciences program at the CUNY Graduate Center spans a broad array of subjects focusing on the earth, its environments, human activities, and the linkages between them.</p>
<p>Our students have the unique opportunity to study both the physical and human environments simultaneously, or to focus on specific subjects within the program’s specializations. The faculty has a strong commitment to education and research in Environmental and Geological Sciences, Environmental Psychology, and Geography.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences" class="uri">https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences</a></p>
<section id="more-information" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="more-information">More Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences/curriculum-and-degree-information">Curriculum and Degree Information</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences/faculty">Faculty</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/events?program=264">Events</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences/students">Current Students</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.gc.cuny.edu/earth-and-environmental-sciences/admissions-and-aid">How to Apply</a></p></li>
</ul>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-01-joining-doctoral-faculty-ees-graduate-center/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2025-01-joining-doctoral-faculty-ees-graduate-center/featured.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Participating APPAM 2024</title>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-appam-climate-change-impacts-and-responses-assessment-politics-and-policy/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="summary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>I will be organizing one session, presenting one paper and one poster in the APPAM 2024 Annual Meeting, welcome to join us and hope to meet you there.</p>
<section id="session" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="session">Session</h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://appam.confex.com/appam/2024/meetingapp.cgi/Session/19958" class="external" target="_blank">Climate Change Impacts and Responses: Assessment, Politics and Policy</a></strong></p>
<p>Thursday, November 21, 2024: 8:30 AM - 10:00 AM</p>
<p>Gaylord National Harbor, National Harbor 15</p>
<p><strong>Abstract</strong>: Climate change presents a multifaceted challenge, impacting energy systems, urban infrastructure, and financial policies. This panel brings together three papers offering comprehensive insights into the assessment, politics, and policy responses to climate change impacts. Paper 1 examines the effects of climate change on the supply-demand match (SDM) in global wind and solar energy systems. Using state-of-the-art climate models, the paper reveals significant reductions in SDM across various regions by the end of the century, emphasizing the need for early adaptation measures in the energy sector. Paper 2 assesses the effectiveness of current conservation projects and funding allocation in meeting the water needs of the Colorado River Basin, particularly in light of ongoing droughts and climate change. Analyzed 593 projects across thirteen programs, the paper shows that while the majority of funds went to municipal projects, it did not result in high amounts of estimated water savings compared to other categories. Paper 3 studies urban stormwater flooding and policy solutions, focusing on marginalized populations in Chicago. Through socio-institutional network analysis and economic assessments, the paper highlights the importance of coordinated efforts at both local and national levels to address flooding disparities and integrate green infrastructure for sustainable urban development. Paper 4 investigates the carbon emission reduction effect of green financial policies in China. By analyzing data from green finance reform and innovation pilot cities, the paper uncovers significant reductions in carbon emission intensity, particularly through industrial structure optimization and green technology innovation, with regional variations in policy effectiveness. These papers collectively contribute valuable empirical evidence and policy implications for understanding and mitigating the complex impacts of climate change on energy systems, urban resilience, and sustainable finance.</p>
<p><strong>Organizer</strong>: Gang He, CUNY-Baruch College</p>
<p><strong>Panel Chair</strong>: Gang He, CUNY-Baruch College</p>
<p><strong>Discussant</strong>:</p>
<p>Mallory Flowers, University of Rhode Island</p>
<p>Emre Hatipoglu, KAPSARC School of Public Policy</p>
<p><strong>Presentations</strong></p>
<p>ID# 52932 <strong>Climate Change Impacts on Planned Supply–Demand Match in Global Wind and Solar Energy Systems</strong></p>
<p>Laibao Liu<sup>1</sup>, <strong>Gang He</strong><sup>2</sup>, Mengxi Wu<sup>3</sup>, Gang Liu<sup>4</sup>, Haoran Zhang<sup>5</sup>, Ying Chen<sup>6</sup>, Jiashu Shen<sup>4</sup> and Shuangcheng Li<sup>4</sup>, (1)The University of Hong Kong, (2)CUNY-Baruch College, (3)The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, (4)Peking University, (5)University College London, (6)University of Birmingham</p>
<p>ID# 54815 <strong>Addressing Water Scarcity in the Colorado River Basin: Review of Conservation Policies</strong></p>
<p><strong>Paloma Avila</strong>, Mehdi Nemati, Daniel Crespo and Ariel Dinar, (1)University of California, Riverside</p>
<p>ID# 52935 <strong>Urban Stormwater Flooding: Policy Solutions Addressing Chicago’s Marginalized Sub-Populations</strong></p>
<p>Darren Christoper, Caleb Hadley, Ron Henderson, Hao Huang, David Lampert, Michael Sansone, <strong>Matthew A. Shapiro</strong>, Brent Stephens and Maria Villalobos Hernandez, Illinois Institute of Technology</p>
<p>ID# 52937 <strong>Carbon Emission Reduction Effect of Green Financial Policy: Empirical Evidence from the Green Finance Reform and Innovation Pilot Zones in China</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ting Guan</strong>, School of Government and Lishan Fu, Beijing Normal University</p>
</section>
<section id="poster" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="poster">Poster</h3>
<p><strong>Health and Climate Benefits of Imported Solar Photovoltaic in the United States</strong></p>
<p>Minghao Qiu<sup>1</sup>, <strong>Gang He</strong><sup>2</sup>, Peter Marcotullio<sup>3</sup>, (1)Stony Brook University, (2)CUNY-Baruch College, (3)CUNY-Hunter College</p>
<p>Friday Poster Reception</p>
<p>Friday, November 22, 2024: 5:00 PM - 6:30 PM</p>
<p>Gaylord National Harbor, Potomac AB</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="relevant-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="relevant-work">Relevant work</h2>
<div id="listing-appam2024" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-default">
<div class="list quarto-listing-default">
<div class="quarto-post image-right" data-index="0" data-categories="cGFwZXIlMkNzbGlkZXM=" data-listing-date-sort="1690171200000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1740835860665" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="2" data-listing-word-count-sort="318">
<div class="thumbnail"><a href="../../posts/2023-07-nenergy-climate-change-impacts-supply-demand-match/index.html" class="no-external">

<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2023-07-nenergy-climate-change-impacts-supply-demand-match/featured.png" class="thumbnail-image">

</a></div>
<div class="body">
<h3 class="no-anchor listing-title">
<a href="../../posts/2023-07-nenergy-climate-change-impacts-supply-demand-match/index.html" class="no-external">Climate change impacts on planned supply–demand match in global wind and solar energy systems</a>
</h3>
<div class="delink listing-description"><a href="../../posts/2023-07-nenergy-climate-change-impacts-supply-demand-match/index.html" class="no-external">
<p>Up to 32% or 44% of non-Antarctic land areas for wind or solar…</p>
</a></div>
</div>
<div class="metadata">
<a href="../../posts/2023-07-nenergy-climate-change-impacts-supply-demand-match/index.html" class="no-external">
<div class="listing-date">
Jul 24, 2023
</div>
<div class="listing-author">
Laibao Liu, Gang He, Mengxi Wu, Gang Liu, Haoran Zhang, Ying Chen, Jiashu Shen, Shuangcheng Li
</div>
</a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">No matching items</div>

</div>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>event</category>
  <category>presentation</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-appam-climate-change-impacts-and-responses-assessment-politics-and-policy/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-appam-climate-change-impacts-and-responses-assessment-politics-and-policy/featured.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fewer than 15% of coal power plant workers in China can easily shift to green jobs by 2060</title>
  <dc:creator>Huihuang Wu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Junfeng Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiurong Hu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yuhan Zhou</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xian Wang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ying Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jianmin Ma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shu Tao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-oneearth-coal-power-workers-shift-green-jobs/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
<span class="screen-reader-only">Note</span>Paper
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>Fewer than 15% of coal power plant workers in China can easily shift to green jobs by 2060<br>
Huihuang Wu, Junfeng Liu, Xiurong Hu, <strong>Gang He</strong>, Yuhan Zhou, Xian Wang, Ying Liu, Jianmin Ma, Shu Tao<br>
<em>One Earth</em> (2024)<br>
DOI: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006">10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>Phasing out coal is essential for climate mitigation but can result in job losses. Although growing literature has reported green job opportunities (e.g., solar technicians) as a potential solution to the displacement of coal sector workers, the extent to which green jobs are easily accessible, regarding co-location and skill requirements, remains unclear. Here, we explore this issue in the context of China’s coal phaseout toward the 2060 carbon neutrality target. Using a coal power plant retirement model of 3,765 coal power units, we find that coal power plant workers must travel long distances (178–242 km) to reach a green job site. When further considering job skill qualifications, in total, fewer than 15% of these workers can easily access green jobs. Postponing the coal phaseout might further exacerbate the job transition challenge. Upstream industries of the renewable energy sector (e.g., electrical machinery), which can be located closer to coal power plants and have better job skill matching, can help alleviate the challenging prospect.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-oneearth-coal-power-workers-shift-green-jobs/featured.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>Spatial relation and skill similarity between coal power plant workers and green jobs</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<p>Published <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S259033222400530X">paper</a></p>
<p>Open access <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S259033222400530X/pdfft?md5=972ca74d333ab90204f8faf849efba7b&amp;pid=1-s2.0-S259033222400530X-main.pdf">pdf</a></p>
<p>Figshare <a href="https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.27394602.v1">data and resources</a></p>
<p>Release <a href="https://deeppolicylab.github.io/news/2024-11-06-one-earth-coal-jobs-transition.html">summary</a></p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="https://d1bxh8uas1mnw7.cloudfront.net/assets/embed.js"></script>
<div class="altmetric-embed" data-badge-popover="right" data-badge-type="donut" data-doi="10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006">

</div>
<span class="__dimensions_badge_embed__" data-doi="10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006" data-hide-zero-citations="true" data-style="small_circle"></span>
<script async="" src="https://badge.dimensions.ai/badge.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-citation"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Citation</h2><div><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">BibTeX citation:</div><pre class="sourceCode code-with-copy quarto-appendix-bibtex"><code class="sourceCode bibtex">@article{wu2024,
  author = {Wu, Huihuang and Liu, Junfeng and Hu, Xiurong and He, Gang
    and Zhou, Yuhan and Wang, Xian and Liu, Ying and Ma, Jianmin and
    Tao, Shu},
  title = {Fewer Than 15\% of Coal Power Plant Workers in {China} Can
    Easily Shift to Green Jobs by 2060},
  journal = {One Earth},
  volume = {7},
  number = {11},
  pages = {1994-2007},
  date = {2024-11-05},
  url = {https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S259033222400530X},
  doi = {10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006},
  langid = {en}
}
</code></pre><div class="quarto-appendix-secondary-label">For attribution, please cite this work as:</div><div id="ref-wu2024" class="csl-entry quarto-appendix-citeas">
Wu, Huihuang, Junfeng Liu, Xiurong Hu, Gang He, Yuhan Zhou, Xian Wang,
Ying Liu, Jianmin Ma, and Shu Tao. 2024. <span>“Fewer Than 15% of Coal
Power Plant Workers in China Can Easily Shift to Green Jobs by
2060.”</span> <em>One Earth</em> 7 (11): 1994–2007. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2024.10.006</a>.
</div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>paper</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-oneearth-coal-power-workers-shift-green-jobs/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-11-oneearth-coal-power-workers-shift-green-jobs/featured.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Grant: Exploring Energy Burden Among the Older Adults and People with Disabilities in New York City Public Housing Communities</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Gang He, Kaifang Luo, Hilary Botein, and Frank Heiland were awarded a SSA grant</description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/images/nyc-mid-town.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>China needs to optimise pumped hydro and battery storage mix</title>
  <dc:creator>Liqun Peng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jiang Lin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gang He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-china-needs-to-optimise-pumped-hydro-and-battery-storage-mix/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Pumped storage hydropower supports China’s transition to renewable energy by generating electricity when the sun is not shining nor the wind blowing.</p>
<p>A pumped hydro facility pumps water uphill into a reservoir when electricity demand and prices are low, usually at night, then releases it back downhill through turbines to generate electricity when demand and prices are high.</p>
<p>The cost of building pumped hydro is high, but a facility lasts for around 60 years, meaning the full life-cycle cost of its power is relatively low. This reliable method for energy storage has witnessed tremendous growth in recent years, linked to the rolling out of China’s carbon emission goals. Between 2015, the year China adopted the Paris Agreement, and 2023, pumped hydro’s installed capacity more than doubled, from 22.8 gigawatts (GW) to 51 GW.</p>
<p>China wants to increase this to over 62 GW by 2025, and around 120 GW by 2030, according to a plan released by the National Energy Administration (NEA) in 2021. There is currently 167 GW of pumped hydro in planning or under construction.</p>
<p>However, our recent <a href="https://international.lbl.gov/publications/role-pumped-hydro-storage-china-s" class="external" target="_blank">study</a> indicates that simply building more pumped hydro might not be the most cost-effective approach to achieve a zero-carbon power system.</p>
<p>Instead, to ensure grid stability and best support the transition to carbon neutrality, existing pumped hydro systems should be optimised while the more economical option of battery storage is widely deployed.</p>
<section id="pumped-hydro-versus-batteries" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pumped-hydro-versus-batteries">Pumped hydro versus batteries</h2>
<p>China’s solar and wind installed capacity has been increasing dramatically, from 120 GW in 2012 to over 1,200 GW in 2024, NEA figures show. This presents challenges to power system reliability given the variable nature of those energy sources. Technologies like pumped hydro and batteries, which store large amounts of energy, are essential in balancing the grid and increasing the power system’s flexibility.</p>
<p>Though pumped hydro has a longer operational lifespan and a lower cost per kilowatt-hour, battery storage is more suitable for widespread application due to its faster construction time (less than six months) compared to pumped hydro (4-5 years), and the fact it doesn’t need specific topography or water availability.</p>
<p>Pumped hydro is cost-effective and efficient for large-scale, long-duration storage, while batteries offer greater flexibility and quicker response times. The two technologies can therefore play complementary roles. As of the end of 2023, China had 86 GW of energy storage in place, with pumped storage accounting for 59.3% and battery storage 40.6%.</p>
<p>As battery costs have been dropping significantly, there has been a boom in the adoption of battery energy storage, leading to a significant uptick in new projects.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-falling-price-of-batteries-may-leave-pumped-hydro-behind" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-falling-price-of-batteries-may-leave-pumped-hydro-behind">The falling price of batteries may leave pumped hydro behind</h2>
<p>We wanted to examine the role of pumped hydro in China’s power system and consider its optimum capacity in 2025 to 2050. To do so we used open-source software called GridPath to build a detailed model of China’s electricity system, including hourly provincial loads, interprovincial transmission constraints, regional wind and solar profiles, and cost projections for renewables and energy storage.</p>
<p>Our findings indicate the NEA’s target for 120 GW of pumped hydro by 2030 will be sufficient to balance variable renewable resources. Meanwhile, the cost of batteries, especially those with a four-hour capacity, will continue to decline and be competitive.</p>
<p>The study therefore shows that from 2025 to 2050, battery-storage capacity could skyrocket from 21 GW to 858 GW. This positions battery storage as a more cost-effective approach to managing the variability of renewable-energy sources and meeting increasing energy demands in the longer term.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-path-forward-for-pumped-hydro-in-china" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-path-forward-for-pumped-hydro-in-china">The path forward for pumped hydro in China</h2>
<p>China has set ambitious targets to expand pumped hydro as part of its strategy to transition to a clean power system, introducing various supportive policies. For example, several provinces, such as Inner Mongolia, Beijing, and Shandong, have exempted pumped hydro storage from the water resource tax.</p>
<p>At the central government level, the National Development and Reform Commission last year introduced a fixed payment for pumped hydro operators based on the capacity of their installations. These “capacity payments” are designed to help operators achieve reasonable returns.</p>
<p>Under the current policies and goals in China, optimising pumped hydro projects has become increasingly important. Our analysis produced the following key findings and recommendations that might provide insight as China refines its pumped hydro strategy.</p>
<p>Firstly, pumped hydro development policies and targets should be integrated in the overall planning of China’s electricity system. Currently, energy storage technologies including pumped hydro are not adequately examined in power system planning. Pumped hydro should be compared systematically with other storage options, generation technologies, and transmission solutions to find the appropriate scale and locations. If not, over-built or mismatched pumped hydro projects could increase power system costs and consumer electricity bills.</p>
<p>Re-evaluating pricing is also important. The current pricing mechanism for pumped hydro, set by authorities based on investment costs, needs refinement as it could potentially lead to cost over-run and over-investment in projects, which could then raise electricity prices unnecessarily. Introducing competition through open bidding for pumped hydro projects can help control project costs and keep electricity tariffs lower.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the wholesale electricity market mechanism needs further improvement. Although energy storage is supposedly allowed to participate in the wholesale electricity market, securing profits remains challenging, as the rules are not clear. Reforms could allow the price to be determined by supply and demand, and provide technology-neutral capacity payments, so that energy storage can compete on a level playing field with other technologies.</p>
<p>Lastly, encouraging interprovincial collaborations for pumped hydro projects can enhance the sharing of electricity or storage and improve regional grid stability. Policymakers should work with their counterparts in neighbouring provinces to create a cooperative framework and align regulations. This will support the optimal deployment of pumped hydro and other system resources, resulting in cost savings for consumers.</p>
<p>Check the original post at <a href="https://dialogue.earth/en/energy/china-needs-to-expand-both-pumped-hydro-and-battery-storage/" class="external" target="_blank">Dialogue Earth</a>.</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>commentary</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-china-needs-to-optimise-pumped-hydro-and-battery-storage-mix/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-china-needs-to-optimise-pumped-hydro-and-battery-storage-mix/featured.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Power Systems Decarbonization: Technology, Policy Responses, and Implications</title>
  <dc:creator>CESE </dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-24-pku-lecture-power-systems-decarbonization/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="title" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="title">Title</h2>
<p>Power Systems Decarbonization: Technology, Policy Responses, and Implications</p>
</section>
<section id="speaker" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="speaker">Speaker</h2>
<p>HE Gang, Baruch College, City University of New York</p>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>“Electrifying energy and decarbonizing electricity” lies at the core of global clean energy transition. In this talk, I will first provide an overview of the current global landscape of electrification and power system transitions. I will then focus on China, which hosts the world’s largest power system, to deep dive into the technological, policy, and systemic challenges of achieving carbon neutrality in the power sector. I will also discuss the technological and policy responses designed to address these challenges. The goal is to explore the complexity of clean power transition under climate change, and examine potential pathways to net-zero emissions, and their environmental, climate, human health, and socio-economic implications.</p>
</section>
<section id="bio" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bio">Bio</h2>
<p>Gang He’s work focuses on energy systems, energy and climate policy, and energy transition. His research advances data-driven, evidence-based energy and climate policy research and offers policy insights for energy decisions and climate actions to achieve carbon neutrality. His leading and collaborative work has appeared in high-impact interdisciplinary and field journals such as Nature, Nature Communications, Nature Energy, One Earth, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, and Energy Policy. His research has been reported by Nature, Scientific American, Carbon Brief, National Geographic, New York Times, E&amp;E News, among others. His work has informed policy processes. He testified for the New York State Climate Leadership and Community Protection Act and has advised the New York State Climate Action Council’s Scoping Plan. He has also been involved in the U.S.-China collaboration on energy and climate change. He received his Ph.D.&nbsp;in Energy and Resources from the University of California, Berkeley. He also holds an M.A.&nbsp;in Climate and Society from Columbia University, and a B.S. and M.S. in Geography from Peking University.</p>
</section>
<section id="flyer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="flyer">Flyer</h2>
<p><a href="https://cese.pku.edu.cn/images/content/2024-10/20241022124634828698.jpg"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/files/flyers/20241024PKU.jpg" class="img-fluid" style="width:90.0%"></a></p>
</section>
<section id="relevant-posts" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="relevant-posts">Relevant posts</h2>
<div id="listing-papers" class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-grid">
<div class="list grid quarto-listing-cols-2">
<div class="g-col-1" data-index="0" data-categories="bmV3cyUyQ2V2ZW50JTJDc2xpZGVzJTJDdmlkZW8lMkNwcmVzZW50YXRpb24=" data-listing-date-sort="1699851600000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1750164456638" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="3" data-listing-word-count-sort="428">
<a href="../../posts/2023-11-switch-china-open-model/index.html" class="quarto-grid-link">
<div class="quarto-grid-item card h-100 card-left">
<p class="card-img-top">
<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2023-11-switch-china-open-model/featured.png" class="thumbnail-image card-img" style="height: 150px;">
</p>
<div class="card-body post-contents">
<h5 class="no-anchor card-title listing-title">
SWITCH-China: Open Source Model for the World’s Largest Power System
</h5>
<div class="card-text listing-description delink">
<p>Open model to study China’s clean power transition</p>
</div>
<div class="card-attribution card-text-small justify">
<div class="listing-author">
SWITCH China
</div>
<div class="listing-date">
Nov 13, 2023
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div></a>
</div>
<div class="g-col-1" data-index="1" data-categories="cGFwZXIlMkNwb3N0ZXI=" data-listing-date-sort="1639976400000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1724076037382" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="2" data-listing-word-count-sort="318">
<a href="../../posts/2021-12-jcp-power-water-carbon/index.html" class="quarto-grid-link">
<div class="quarto-grid-item card h-100 card-left">
<p class="card-img-top">
<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2021-12-jcp-power-water-carbon/featured.jpg" class="thumbnail-image card-img" style="height: 150px;">
</p>
<div class="card-body post-contents">
<h5 class="no-anchor card-title listing-title">
Long-term transition of China’s power sector under carbon neutrality target and water withdrawal constraint
</h5>
<div class="card-text listing-description delink">
<p>Low cost renewables reduced the need for CCS by 80%, and water…</p>
</div>
<div class="card-attribution card-text-small justify">
<div class="listing-author">
Chao Zhang, Gang He, Josiah Johnston, Lijin Zhong
</div>
<div class="listing-date">
Dec 20, 2021
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div></a>
</div>
<div class="g-col-1" data-index="2" data-categories="cGFwZXI=" data-listing-date-sort="1589515200000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1762864736126" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="5" data-listing-word-count-sort="858">
<a href="../../posts/2020-05-ncomms-rapid-re-cost/index.html" class="quarto-grid-link">
<div class="quarto-grid-item card h-100 card-left">
<p class="card-img-top">
<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2020-05-ncomms-rapid-re-cost/featured.png" class="thumbnail-image card-img" style="height: 150px;">
</p>
<div class="card-body post-contents">
<h5 class="no-anchor card-title listing-title">
Rapid Cost Decrease of Renewables and Storage Accelerates the Decarbonization of China’s Power System
</h5>
<div class="card-text listing-description delink">
<p>A renewable dominant pathway is not just technogical sound, but also cost…</p>
</div>
<div class="card-attribution card-text-small justify">
<div class="listing-author">
Gang He, Jiang Lin, Froylan Sifuentes, Xu Liu, Nikit Abhyankar, Amol Phadke
</div>
<div class="listing-date">
May 15, 2020
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div></a>
</div>
<div class="g-col-1" data-index="3" data-categories="cGFwZXIlMkNwb3N0ZXI=" data-listing-date-sort="1462680000000" data-listing-file-modified-sort="1743435500981" data-listing-date-modified-sort="NaN" data-listing-reading-time-sort="2" data-listing-word-count-sort="268">
<a href="../../posts/2016-est-switch-china/index.html" class="quarto-grid-link">
<div class="quarto-grid-item card h-100 card-left">
<p class="card-img-top">
<img loading="lazy" data-src="../../posts/2016-est-switch-china/featured.png" class="thumbnail-image card-img" style="height: 150px;">
</p>
<div class="card-body post-contents">
<h5 class="no-anchor card-title listing-title">
SWITCH-China: A Systems Approach to Decarbonizing China’s Power System
</h5>
<div class="card-text listing-description delink">
<p>SWITCH-China, an integrated model for power sector decarbonization.</p>
</div>
<div class="card-attribution card-text-small justify">
<div class="listing-author">
Gang He, Anne-Perrine Avrin, James H. Nelson, Josiah Johnston, Ana Mileva, Jianwei Tian, Daniel M. Kammen
</div>
<div class="listing-date">
May 8, 2016
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div></a>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">No matching items</div>

</div>
</section>
<section id="references" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="he_rapid_2020">Gang He et al. <span>“Rapid Cost Decrease of Renewables and Storage Accelerates the Decarbonization of China’s Power System,”</span> <em>Nature Communications</em> 11, no. 1 (May 19, 2020): 2486, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-16184-x">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-16184-x</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="heSWITCHChinaSystemsApproach2016">Gang He et al. <span>“<span>SWITCH</span>-<span>China</span>: <span>A</span> <span>Systems</span> <span>Approach</span> to <span>Decarbonizing</span> <span>China</span>’s <span>Power</span> <span>System</span>,”</span> <em>Environmental Science &amp; Technology</em> 50, no. 11 (June 2016): 5467–73, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.6b01345">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.6b01345</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="zhangLongtermTransitionChina2021">Chao Zhang et al. <span>“Long-Term Transition of <span>China</span>’s Power Sector Under Carbon Neutrality Target and Water Withdrawal Constraint,”</span> <em>Journal of Cleaner Production</em> 329 (December 2021): 129765, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129765">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129765</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="linLargeBalancingAreas2022">Jiang Lin et al. <span>“Large Balancing Areas and Dispersed Renewable Investment Enhance Grid Flexibility in a Renewable-Dominant Power System in <span>China</span>,”</span> <em>iScience</em> 25, no. 2 (February 2022): 103749, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2022.103749">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2022.103749</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="pengHeterogeneousEffectsBattery2023">Liqun Peng et al. <span>“Heterogeneous Effects of Battery Storage Deployment Strategies on Decarbonization of Provincial Power Systems in <span>China</span>,”</span> <em>Nature Communications</em> 14, no. 1 (August 2023): 4858, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-40337-3">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-40337-3</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="luoAcceleratingChinaPower2023">Qian Luo et al. <span>“Accelerating <span>China</span>’s Power Sector Decarbonization Can Save Lives: Integrating Public Health Goals into Power Sector Planning Decisions,”</span> <em>Environmental Research Letters</em> 18, no. 10 (September 2023): 104023, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/acf84b">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/acf84b</a>.</span></li>
<li><span class="citation" data-cites="yangRegionalDisparitiesHealth2024">Haozhe Yang et al. <span>“Regional Disparities in Health and Employment Outcomes of <span>China</span>’s Transition to a Low-Carbon Electricity System,”</span> <em>Environmental Research: Energy</em> 1, no. 2 (April 2024): 025001, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1088/2753-3751/ad3bb8">https://doi.org/10.1088/2753-3751/ad3bb8</a>.</span></li>
</ul>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>



</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>event</category>
  <category>presentation</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-24-pku-lecture-power-systems-decarbonization/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-10-24-pku-lecture-power-systems-decarbonization/featured.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Climate Week NYC 2024: Clean Energy Global Supply Chains Panel</title>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/</link>
  <description>Join us to discuss Role of Clean Energy Global Supply Chains in Achieving Climate Goals during Climate Week NYC 2024.</description>
  <category>event</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/images/climate-week-logo.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="65" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Included in World’s Top 2% Scientists List 2024</title>
  <dc:creator>Stanford/Elsevier </dc:creator>
  <link>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><a href="https://topresearcherslist.com/Home/Profile/858833"><img src="https://drganghe.github.io/files/awards/top2scientists.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></a></p>
</figure>
</div>
<figcaption>The database mistakenly references my former employer where I’m still an Affiliated Faculty. I have since joined CUNY-Baruch College.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<section id="acknowledgment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="acknowledgment">Acknowledgment</h2>
<p>Grateful to be included in the <strong><a href="https://topresearcherslist.com/Home/Profile/858833" class="external" target="_blank">Stanford/Elsevier Top 2% Scientists List 2024</a></strong> in three subfields:</p>
<ul>
<li>Environmental Sciences</li>
<li>Energy</li>
<li>Enabling &amp; Strategic Technologies</li>
</ul>
<p>I want to take a moment to thank my family, current and former students, visiting scholars, mentors, collaborators, funders, editors, reviewers, and colleagues for their invaluable support.</p>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<p>Baruch News, <a href="https://newscenter.baruch.cuny.edu/news/baruch-college-faculty-included-in-worlds-top-scientist-list/" class="external" target="_blank">Baruch College Faculty Included in World’s Top Scientist List</a></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet blockquote"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🎉 Congratulations to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MarxeFaculty?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MarxeFaculty</a> Deborah Balk <a href="https://twitter.com/CIDR_NYC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CIDR_NYC</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/j_jgreene?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@j_jgreene</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/DrGangHe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrGangHe</a>, along with six other <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BaruchFaculty?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BaruchFaculty</a> members, for being named to <a href="https://twitter.com/Stanford?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Stanford</a> University and Elsevier’s “World’s Top 2% Scientists” list for 2024! 🌍✨ <br><br>👉🔗 <a href="https://t.co/fdUPQIZoRR">https://t.co/fdUPQIZoRR</a> <a href="https://t.co/7UVra18g7S">pic.twitter.com/7UVra18g7S</a></p>— Marxe School (@BaruchMarxe) <a href="https://twitter.com/BaruchMarxe/status/1850920524072833515?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<div class="quarto-video"><video id="video_shortcode_videojs_video1" class="video-js vjs-default-skin vjs-fluid" controls="" preload="auto" data-setup="{}" title=""><source src="../../files/videos/world-top-scientists.mp4"></video></div>
<p>Source: Marxe School</p>
</section>
<section id="about-worlds-top-2-scientists" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="about-worlds-top-2-scientists">About World’s Top 2% Scientists</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Stanford University’s list of “World’s Top 2%” scientists is based on a 2% or above percentile rank, or the top 100,000 by c-score (with and without self-citations). This prestigious list identifies the world’s leading researchers, representing approximately 2% of all scientists worldwide. It encompasses standardised data on citations, h-index, and a wide range of bibliometric indicators. Researchers are classified into 22 scientific fields and 174 sub-fields, drawing from Scopus data provided by Elsevier through ICSR Lab.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learn more <a href="https://topresearcherslist.com/Home/AboutUs">here</a>.</p>
<!--Include social share buttons-->
<!-- 
AddToAny check more: https://www.addtoany.com/buttons/for/website 
Using includes will make edits easier, will only need to add or remove button here if needed.
https://quarto.org/docs/authoring/includes.html
-->
<div class="a2a_kit a2a_kit_size_32 a2a_default_style">
<p><a class="a2a_dd" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share"></a> <a class="a2a_button_linkedin"></a> <a class="a2a_button_bluesky"></a> <a class="a2a_button_facebook"></a> <a class="a2a_button_whatsapp"></a> <a class="a2a_button_wechat"></a> <a class="a2a_button_sina_weibo"></a> <a class="a2a_button_copy_link"></a> <a class="a2a_button_email"></a></p>
</div>
<script async="" src="https://static.addtoany.com/menu/page.js"></script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>recognition</category>
  <category>video</category>
  <guid>https://drganghe.github.io/posts/2024-09-16-stanford-elsevier-top-2percent-scientists/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://drganghe.github.io/files/awards/Top2Percent.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="81" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
